<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>funtional programming on Susan Potter</title>
    <link>/tags/funtional-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in funtional programming on Susan Potter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/funtional-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Profunctors: An exploration, Part 1</title>
      <link>/software/profunctors-an-exploration-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/profunctors-an-exploration-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Alex on Unsplash  Notes:    This post was originally adapted from a gist in 2018: https://gist.github.com/mbbx6spp/51bf2b694dc9bbf81b60f2f616453eb3    The Gist was moved to a snippet. Goals     This series explores one kind of motivation and the building blocks of Profunctors with an aim to introduce the concepts informally while introducing terminology along the way. After assembling the parts of a Profunctor the reader should start to see how packaging these operators as a pair allows library designers to offer a declarative interface for their clients to build custom codecs with a small number of primitives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parametricity: A Practitioners Guide</title>
      <link>/software/parametricity-a-practitioners-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/parametricity-a-practitioners-guide/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   What software developer likes surprises, especially in production? Not me. At least not when I am on call. ;)  Wouldn&amp;#39;t it be great if we were able to reason about our code to make our lives as simple as possible when debugging or eliminate debugging altogether?  The big idea of parametricity is that from parametric (or generic) &amp;#34;pure&amp;#34; functions we can determine interesting properties (and more of them) from the parametric (generic) types than the equivalent function fixed with specific types.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>