<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>profunctors on Susan Potter</title>
    <link>/tags/profunctors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in profunctors on Susan Potter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/profunctors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Profunctors: An exploration, Part 2</title>
      <link>/software/profunctors-an-exploration-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/profunctors-an-exploration-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Originally adapted from a gist: https://gist.github.com/mbbx6spp/51bf2b694dc9bbf81b60f2f616453eb3 Moved to the original Gist to a snippet.  This is a continuation from part 1.  Profunctors are a remarkably practical abstraction for many activities software developers are concerned with on a day to day basis. Back to basics (Functors)   In one direction (e.g. decoding, deserializing, decrypting, validating) we start with data that needs some transformation yielding new types of data to be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profunctors: An exploration, Part 1</title>
      <link>/software/profunctors-an-exploration-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/profunctors-an-exploration-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Notes:    Originally adapted from a gist in 2018: https://gist.github.com/mbbx6spp/51bf2b694dc9bbf81b60f2f616453eb3    Moved the original Gist to a snippet.   Motivation   Profunctors are a remarkably practical abstraction for many activities that software developers are concerned with on a day to day basis. This first part of the Profunctor series will introduce example motivations all software developers face when doing typical application development.  Today a significant amount of software development in-the-small for web/native apps or backend services concerns the following activity pairs:   Encoding &amp;amp; decoding    We need to ensure that encoding is consistent, e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>