<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on Susan Potter</title>
    <link>/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on Susan Potter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 18:45:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Recursion Schemes</title>
      <link>/blogs/software/2018/10/practical-recursion-schemes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 18:45:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/software/2018/10/practical-recursion-schemes/</guid>
      <description>Recursive data types   Recursive data structures pop up all over in software from general-purpose structures like lists and binary trees to more application-specific structures like this AST from a simple business rules engine: data BusinessRule input output = IfThenElse (input -&amp;gt; Bool) (BusinessRule input output) (BusinessRule input output) | Return (input -&amp;gt; output) | Stop  Functor  Foldable   The Foldable class gives you the ability to process the elements of a structure one-at-a-time, discarding the shape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles of economics applied to software development, reliability engineering, and technical leadership</title>
      <link>/blogs/software/2017/06/economic-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 15:42:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/software/2017/06/economic-theory/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite subjects as a lay person is economics. I have found many useful applications of methods and concepts to my work in software development, technical leadership, and reliability engineering roles.  This is a post to share some of these. A few ideas from economics, an introduction first   Below is an overview of ideas from economics that have resonated with me at work:   Opportunity cost    Looking at what you lose by choosing a specific activity over others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>